<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A message from the spirit of truth, unto the holy seed, who are chosen out of the world, and are lovers, and followers of the light</title>
            <author>Naylor, James, 1617?-1660.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 33 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A52704</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12493120</idno>
  <idno type="VID">62426</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240950176</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing N298</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R23114</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">12493120</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A52704)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 62426)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 769:32)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A message from the spirit of truth, unto the holy seed, who are chosen out of the world, and are lovers, and followers of the light</title>
                  <author>Naylor, James, 1617?-1660.</author>
                  <author>R. T. (Rebecca Travers), 1609-1688.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>16 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for T. Simmons ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1658.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"To the reader" signed: R.T. [i.e. Rebekah Travers]</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>John Latta </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:62426:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:62426:1"/>
            <p>A MESSAGE FROM THE SPIRIT OF TRUTH, UNTO THE Holy Seed, WHO Are chosen out of the world, and are lovers, and followers of the LIGHT.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Thomas Simmons</hi> at the Bull and Mouth near Aldersgate, 1658.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:62426:2"/>
            <head>TO THE READER:</head>
            <p>YOU Lovers and followers of the Light, to you is this Mes<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sage sent, in it abide, that the glory of the onely begotten of the Father, you may behold, and be changed from glory to glory: fill not your heads, but feel the life of what in this fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing paper is declared. For though the Thief, the Boaster, the proud and exalted ones have, or may cover themselves with like words; yet this birth never was, is, or shall be brought forth, but by the espoused Virgin; pure, chaste, and spot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lesse, true and abiding innocency; far distant from all feigned purity, which many being puffed up in their vain minds, have or may intrude into things they know not, and so de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive the simple by a voluntary humility, and worshipping of An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gels: these hold not fast the head which gives the life to every Member; he that is without beginning of dayes, or end of life; by whom, and for whom all things were made: to him shall eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry knee bow, who filleth all in all, of whose fullnesse he hath re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, grace for grace, who in these following lines salutes the whole elect of God every where, plentifully giving forth of the great Mystery of godlinesse, hidden from ages and generations, now made manifest to the meek and upright in heart, who in the unfeigned love abide, which endures for ever.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>R. T.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="treatise">
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:62426:2"/>
            <head>A MESSAGE FROM THE <hi>SPIRIT of TRƲTH,</hi> UNTO THE Holy Seed.</head>
            <div type="part">
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">D</seg>Ear friends, Brethren, and Sisters, of the Seed of <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>braham,</hi> partakers with him in the holy call, and who in his faith wait for that glory and inheritance immortall, which every one of you shall receive at the appearance of the great God, and his Son Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sus Christ, to you all be peace, truth and love increased, wherein you may be established to the end of your calling.</p>
               <p>That which is set before me in the Spirit of truth, and for which my soul travels, and breaths after in the whole creation (but especially in you who are already called thereunto) I am moved to impart unto you, thereby to stir you up earnestly to presse on towards the appearance of that to which you are called in one, which is no other than what hath been holden forth from the beginning, even the onely begotten of the Father, filled with grace and truth, for the obtaining whereof, you that are faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full have denied the delights of this present world, and do daily undergoe the enmity thereof. Of whose appearance many of you have received a certain hope which cannot be shaken, and a measure of him some are come to in the same Spirit, who have seen, felt, and handled of his appearance, and have received of his fulnesse, wherein alone you excell, and are able to hold forth that life in the power of obedience, meeknesse, and fear, which no
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:62426:3"/> form nor knowledge without is able to bear or bring forth, which is that alone wherein I rejoyce in you, and not onely so, but find cause in heart to magnifie that goodnesse, and glorious power of God, already manifested in you, and through you to the world, whose praises will daily increase, as his vertues ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear in you; which that you, and all the number of called ones may increase in and grow to the age, stature, and full appearance of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, is the full desire of my soul, and that which will give us an assured joy and perfect peace in one, when knowledge will vanish, and that which is in part shall be done away.</p>
               <p>Wherefore you that have received the Spirit of Prophecy, and that light out of darknesse, which lets you see what manner of one the Son of God must be at his appearing in Spirit and power, holinesse, and great glory, I beseech you that none of you sit down at rest in this sight, nor be you puffed up there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with, as though you had already attained, lest thereby the Enemy prevail to assault you above what is meet, and so o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers lesse in wisdome, who are more lowly in Spirit step in before you, and obtain that Crown and glory to which you were called, and so while you feed on the knowledge you loose, the life, but that every one wait in the light to feel the power and life, of the Sonne of God manifest in your bodies giving you victory over your own spirits, and raising you up out of death into the life of the Prophecies, that you may all know the true worship in Spirit, and what you bow unto, that hence<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forth you may be servants of righteousnesse, begotten and not made, which onely hath food able to satisfie your thirsting souls, that you may all feel the onely begotten of God in vertue, and power, working mightily the work of the Father, and destroy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the work of the Devil in every particular, for hereuuto were you first called, that you should inherit eternall life and power, the true riches of grace in righteousnesse, and to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive a Kingdome that cannot be moved, but that is able to keep you against all assaults of the enemy, which riches is Gods one<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly begotten, in whom is received of the perfect fulnesse of God, which is onely able to satisfie all fears and supply all wants, in all who attain to his appearance.</p>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:62426:3"/>
               <p>And further I beseeth you, that you satisfie not your selves onely with a feeling of this working in you, but that you dili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gently attend an entrance thereinto, that you may put him on whom the Father begetteth and formeth in you, that your souls may be bathed and anointed therein. And not onely so, but that you bring him forth before all men, even him the one<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly begotten Sonne of God in meeknesse, long suffering, in pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tience, in righteousnesse, in godly holinesse, and all his vertues; the living image of him, by whom he is begotten: that it may appear to all men whose you are, and who possesseth the ves<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sel, and what he is that appears therein; that it may be seen and confessed that God is in you of a truth revealed in his onely begotten; For this is he, to whom at his appearance eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry tongue shall confesse, and every heart be struck with fear; though the form of his beauty, and visage of his glory hath (amongst false Births, and fained Professions) been more marred than any mans, who instead of bringing forth into the world the onely begotten of God, to convince and condemne the world of all ungodlinesse, and save them from it, have brought forth the conceivings of their own brains, and the child born to them is no Saviour, but their birth hath left them in the world, and one with it, who are now turning the words of Christ against his works, and their power to withstand his appea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance in others, who is the same which was, and is, and is to come to all generations.</p>
               <p>So that in stead of holding forth that Spirituall power of perfect Redemption from above, to save his people from their sinnes, and set them at liberty from the bondage of corruption, to serve God in the new man, the Sonne of righteousnesse, of peace, and holinesse, Gods image, there appears the Sonne of wickednesse in every form, at liberty, and pleaded for, the I<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage and power of all unrighteousnesse and ungodlinesse, preached and set up: so that the very faith and hope of Gods appearance in their generation is destroyed. So these not wait<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in faith, single in the begettings of God from above, to see in patience that formed, born and brought forth, but mix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing with their reasonings and wisdome from below have not attained his appearance, but have turned the truth of God in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:62426:4"/> a lye, his glory into shame; wherefore God hath given them up to believe their own conceivings: And you hath he cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led into that glorious hope, and powerfull faith, wherein you nowstand; and them he hath left to be heirs of the corrupti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons of this world, which they have minded more then himself; where now many of them are the great opposers of his appea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance, who were once called to bear a measure of his testimony in spirituall life and power.</p>
               <p>And now dear friends, the called of God you are, unto the day of his coming, whose light hath shined out of darknesse giving you a knowledge in this great mystery, and hope, and a power you have received from above, whereby you are come nearer the day, than those before you, and many have denied the world, and their Inheritance, that you might stand single in hope thereof; Now the day is yours if you be watchfull, and faithfull thereto; that you mix not with the earthly seed, nor bring forth a false birth, but that your hearts be single, and open to receive him from above, the heavenly seed in the will of God, and not of your selves; the Sonne of righteous<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesse, the Fathers glory, who hath the living Image and pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er of God, to make all Sonnes and Daughters of the most high, confortable to himself, and heirs with him of the same Kingdome, glory, and power; even as many of you as so re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive him, as to put him on as he is, and so walk in him as the begotten of God, children of the most holy, whom he hath counted worthy of so high a calling, as to receive his name, power, and glory, and to bear testimony what he is before all men, and to hold forth the power that you have in his name, and Image, above all names and forms, in heaven or in earth; and this with all diligence, meeknesse and fear, lest Satan de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive you of that simplicity that is in him, and so you come short of his glory, and others be called. Now quit your selves as the beloved of God; cast off every weight which would hinder your attaining him, that in the light is set before you; crucifie every affection after the earthly, and put away all the cares, and pleasures that would choak this seed, and what ever would mix in your minds, or plead for a place in your hearts, let it be to you as an accursed thing, that the blessing of <hi>Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham</hi>
                  <pb n="7" facs="tcp:62426:4"/> may come upon you, and through you to manifest to all the world, and that the holy name of Christ may be glorified in you which hath long been polluted through such as have pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fessed it in a contrary nature.</p>
               <p>For this is he to whose appearance in the world every tongue shall be made to confesse, and the Angels of God shall worship him, for he is the glory of God, and power of righte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ousnesse in heaven and in earth, Gods love and good will a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongst men, and in him is the Father revealed, whom no eye hath seen. You that have received him, and hold him forth, are the light of the world, let him shine to the glory of your Father; It's you that hold forth the foundation of faith; he being lifted up will draw all men to him: hold him forth clear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, as you receive him from above, and there is that in every Conscience, that will answer to his appearance; for God hath not left him without witnesse: So that he that believes not is condemned already in himself, because he believes not in that onely begotten of God, whom the Father hath s<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nt into the world. If he do not that work in you, which none other can do, then how should any believe, or confesse that it is he But at his appearance his works shall declare him and leave all without excuse.</p>
               <p>His righteousnesse, his meeknesse, his patient sufferings, his lowly mindednesse, his faith and obedience to the Father, his love and tender compassion towards all men, being richly fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nished with all manner of godlinesse, shall declare him whose Image he bears, and whose Sonne he is, and from whence he comes, for the earth hath not those fruits, power, and glory: Thus shall he be be glorified in his Saints, and admired in all them that believe, and receive his testimony; And in this birth you shall not onely save your selves, but hold forth salvation to all that hear thereof.</p>
               <p>Wherefore as you professe that holy calling above others, so in fear of God take heed what you bring forth, be sober and watch diligently in that which is from above, lest the e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nemy prevail to mix somewhat of your own to hold forth in his name, that hath not the nature, power nor purity of the
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:62426:5"/> Sonne of God, and that being above spoil you of his appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance, and marre the true Image, which you will find the envi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous one seeks to devour upon all occasions, that alone having power over the head of the Serpent; wherefore see that you be covered with him alone, as he is from heaven.</p>
               <p>But above all things, I beseech you put him on as he is the Son of Gods love, and so hold him forth towards all men, but especially towards the brethren, so much the more as this being that which the enemy hath cast long upon the children of light (to wit) want of love, taking his advantage while the way hath been preparing thereto, and the Spirit of judgement and burning hath passed on the old building, a time of sorrow and pulling down, dressing the house where love should dwell; So that though the root of the matter was in it, yet could not in that time spring forth towards others, nor indeed be fully shed abroad in the heart, while that is there which God hates: which love many have now received, and it is full time to bring forth, him so begotten in you, lest any selfishnesse ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear in his stead, and so prevent you of that which is most ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellent; But that you all may put him on, as he is manifest from the Fathers bosome, and that you be cloathed therewith, from heaven, so plentifully that you may have to cast over a Brothers nakednesse, a garment of the same love, who came from above to lay down his life for his enemies, and of the same power, who can forgive sinnes and offences, above seven times a day, beholding each others with that good eye which waits for the soul and not for the sinne, which covers, and over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comes the evil with the good, that with him you may be per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect in love, judging and receiving one another; in the increase of God, and not in that which is for destruction, giving more abundant honour to him that lacketh. that in the body be no schisme, nor defile one another, nor keep alive a Brothers ini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quity, nor blot out the name, and appearing of the holy seed in the least, but keep the Lord in your eye, and the evils shall dye and vanish away from amongst you, and the appearance shall be the Lords, and to him shall the gathering of the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions be, hungry souls shall see, and be satisfied with his
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:62426:5"/> likenesse, and all that behold his beauty shall confesse unto him: and in him shall the upright heart delight, for at his coming shall he establish the Throne of righteousnesse, and measure every appearance, and correct every false judgment, and that which ensnares the simple will he cast out, for by the power of his appearance shall every thing be tryed, and peace proclaimed in the name of righteousnesle alone, for that which <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s not like him will not be able to stand before his appearance. But we know that when he appears we shall be like him; he that hath this hope purifies himself even as he is pure, that he may be seen in him at his coming.</p>
               <p>Now dear friends is your sound gone to the ends of the earth, and God hath made you famous amongst your enemies, in that you have begun to confesse his name, and nature, and that he is in you whom many are looking for here and there, and now the eyes of people and Nations are upon you to see your end, and now your glory is in putting him on, and cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring you with him, a Lamb without blemish, before God and man, that in him you may obtain good report, unreproveable, and holy, so shall you stop the way of the destroyer, and put an end to all false conceptions, and revive the hope of <hi>Israel.</hi> Let his innocency be your armour, and put your trust in his truth, for your salvation. The time is full come for you to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare what he is to you, with boldness with a confession beyond words: for this appearance of him in love is that which shall judge all likenesses, and try all spirits, actions, judgments, and appearances, and by this shall you all be measured, what spirits you are of and all spirits in the world, for he shall bring every hidden, formed, fained thing to light, at his coming, and what ever hath not this love in it, is not his, nor begotten of God, but he that hath this love is begotten of God, and hath him, the Father and the Son, the end of the Law and the Prophets, the substance and life of all knowledge, faith and works; the root and ground of every good gift, for herein are we made perfect in love, that we may have boldness in the day of judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, because we have put him on, &amp; dwel in him who is love and as he is, so are we in this world. But he that loveth not
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:62426:6"/> is not made perfect in faith, in knowledge, in judgment, having not learned Christ herein, therefore by this he must be judged himself. So blessed is he that judges nothing before the time, who condemns not himself, wherein he judges another; all judgment being committed to him that can lay down his life for his enemies. Therefore happy are you if you have him on first, for when he appears his judgment is true, and shall stand, when all that hath come before him shall pass away, for him alone hath the Father sealed.</p>
               <p>So dearly beloved ones, my soul breaths towards you here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in, that in all your severall gifts, and administrations, this Son of God be your eye and end, the beauty and glory of the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, that the hope thereof to attain, may stay you in all try<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>als and temptations, knowing that in him alone is your lasting peace, and that which doth now befall you in all your afflicti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons is to shake all other appearances, that way may be made for him alone, whose Image and life, none can judge nor condemn. And the day is come, that happy is that man who hath nothing else to glory in, and this know that the appea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance of God in his own begotten, is your glory; and if any man boast himself and not herein, when he is weighed there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with he will be found wanting, the sound thereof will not save him.</p>
               <p>As the same spirit from whence this comes, moves in any one, so let them send it abroad a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongst the called of God, to be read and known.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:62426:6"/>
               <p>Come forth you children of light, come forth, depart out of the world, touch not the unclean thing, that the ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly one may make his appearance amongst you: make hast to the day of your God. If he shine forth salvation is with you, but he cannot appear in that heart where the world is retain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed. If you be like the world it will own you; but that image which it receives not, is your everlasting glory and beauty. So mind what works in the vessel; for now must every childe appear like his Father, and must bring to light of what spirit he is begotten: and only blessed is he that comes in the name of the Lord with power and great glory, that which the world is ashamed of, is that with which the Son of God is glorified, and again must be glorified, he that bears the iniquities of men, and is fill'd with reproach, and yet appears without sin, is our Saviour. And a Lamb without spot must take away the sin of the world; his manifestation destroyes the work of the Devil; in a body prepared he delights to performe the councill of God, and to bring hidden things to light; that he may speak mysteries to the wise therein, and hold forth away to the simple leading out of the snares of subtilty.</p>
               <p>Wherefore all that love his appearance, and seek the face of redemption, love that which prepares his way to his appea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance in his Temple; that which breaks down the will of man, and as a fire goes before him; which is that baptism with which all that will receive him must be baptised into death. So when sorrow, anguish, and tribulation comes upon you, rejoyce, and fly not. This comes to destroy nothing but de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>struction; and to kill that which keeps you from eternall life, and to prepare a way for your peace, and a place for everlast<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing righteousnesse to dwell in you. For truly friends, in the threshing floor must the Altar be set up, and where God an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>swers by fire, there must his house be built: And as many as look to the end of this, may not despise correction, nor faint under the hand of reproof.</p>
               <p>That is good which brings down into the depth, where the wonders of God are learned, for he that will labour in Gods Vineyard must know every seed, and its roote; what feeds it, and what famisheth it, and the ground of every weed, and
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:62426:7"/> of every curse. This many may see, when it's come to a Tree, brancheth, and brings forth fruit: but then its strong and powerfull, and not easily pluckt up, seldom got down wi<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hout fire and much sorrow, therefore blessed is that eye thats lowly, &amp; diligent, which sees every severall appearance, that he may slay the seed of wickedness ere it bud, and not suffer the enmity to take root: for he that suffers divers seeds shall have sorrow therein; and he that sowes amongst thorns and bryars must reap trouble; and where this kind is suffered to grow, there is torment to themselves, and trouble to others; for how should the thistle change its nature?</p>
               <p>So all that desire peace, prepare a place that the seed there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of may grow alone, and the Sun thereof may arise and shine clearly, that nothing may grieve his holy spirit, for <hi>Iacob</hi> must dwell alone, and not be numbred among the rest of the Nations, neither hath the Lamb fellowship with the beasts of the field.</p>
               <p>Now as you have seen the Image of the earthly, and felt his power, and inclination to earthly things, captivating your mindes downward, to things below: even so must you bear the Image of the heavenly, if he reign that comes from above. Till then think not you are perfect, nor have attained to the resurrection of the dead. For this I know of him, in whom your life is hid, that as he ariseth, he shall as strongly lead your mindes into the heavenly, as ever you were captivated with the earthly. So he that can read the figure, rejoyce in hope concerning him that is to come; yet let none glory in the sight of this knowledge, but press into the life thereof, that God may be seen and glorified in you. For as he that hath gone much out with his mind, and hath drunk in aboun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dance of the earthly, is become the most subtle, selfish, and hard, and filled with all unrighteousness, till he become incu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable: even so he that returns in, and drinks abundantly of the heavenly, doth become simple, innocent and harmless, separate from all ungodliness, till he become incorruptible, and receive power to attain the Son of God, whose image de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clares the Father, from whence he is: for he that hath seen the Son, hath seen the Father, and he that hath the Son hath
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:62426:7"/> the Father also. So dear friends, behold the end of your calling and glory of your profession, your life in this world and eternall inheritance, for the which to attaine, we endure all things; for which sufferings, and patience, we have a cloud of witnesses.</p>
               <p>So we follow not fables and fancies (as some suppose) but every one as he is proved herein, is able to set to his seal, even to the day of the Lord, with them that are gone before, whose spirits herein are perfected.</p>
               <p>Wherefore dearly beloved of God, for his name sake I be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>seech you, be zealous for his appearance, and with meekness and fear instruct the ignorant, who oppose themselves; com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort the weak; in all things leading with a life that cannot be blamed, knowing how manifold your labour of love is doubled, in everlasting glory, as he comes to be made manifest to the world. And the Lord God of power strengthen all your hands, by the appearance of his love; that by the shedding of it abroad in your hearts, you may be made able to overcome the world, and willing to give your necks to the yoake of Christ, and to bear the burthens of the weak, till the brother<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood arise, and the body of Christ be perfected in one; that none of you suffer an evill eye or eare, which delights to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold the weakness of others; but that your whole delight be to waite for the appearance of God in all, and to behold his face in them, rather then their failings. And as this arises in every particular, it shall be a sure token to you for good, and that you are passed from the love of evill, unto the love of God the Father, and the Son. And what you delight in, shall be your inheritance. And as you grow herein, so shall he whom you love to see, delight to make his appearance a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongst you, and to walk in you; and you shall not seek his face in vain, but with his likeness shall be satisfied, and shall praise the beauty of his appearance.</p>
               <p>Thus in honour preferring one another, you shall know, that the power of love is a ministration of life, to that which is to be beloved.</p>
               <p>Who will be on the Lords part, now in this day of dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness, when iniquity is growing to the full? and the manchilde
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:62426:8"/> is to be born above it? And who will give up the vessel to bear his name against the enmity that is now arising. And who will be glorified with the Lamb? Blessed and happy is he that is found worthy to follow him out of the world, bearing his reproach. To as many as receive him, he gives power to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come the Sons of God.</p>
               <p>But he that will bear his name must receive his nature, and himself also so walk, even as he walked; his name, is power over sin, and the world. So the servants of sin, and the world cannot bear it; he that bears his name, must bear it in his life, and power least he blaspheme. Of flesh and blood it is not born, nor by the will of man is it manifest, it's he that's borne again who hath his witness in himself, that must bear his name before the world for a witnesse against them, who hath that life in him which testifies against the deeds thereof; but who bows thereto betrays him, and proves false in his testimony.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Moses</hi> in his house, made all things in likenesse of the pat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tern, so it became a Tabernacle of witnesse to all the Nations (of the true God therein) and against all there false Gods, and false worships, and herein was he faithfull to him that called him, and to all that beheld the pattern he preached Gods presence, dwelling in the Tabernacle made with hands. How much more must he that bears the name of Christ, fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low the pattern, and sute his example, holding forth a Taber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nacle of witnesse, and preaching the presence of the true God therein, and against all the world, their false births, false ways, and worships, herein proving faithfull to him that hath called thereto; and to all that beholds, holding forth that holiness is his habitation here on earth, as it is in heaven, bear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a lively testimony thereof, by the Tabernacle of witnesse, conformable to the heavenly example in all things. And to this end Christ descended, walked, and suffered on earth, leaving an example to all that follow his steps, wherein as in a lively Oracle. God is found, in all that's builded after his Image, and seek in his name, and nature, for the immortallity that dwel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leth therein. Now God was not to be found in the Tabernacle of <hi>Molech</hi> (though sought never so earnestly) but in the Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bernacle of witness, built according to the pattern; neither
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:62426:8"/> is he now to be found in the Image of the world: nor is his name born in that nature though professed never so zealously. Therefore let every one that nameth the name of the Lord depart from iniquity; The seed of evill doers bears not the testimony of Christ, but against him.</p>
               <p>Did they blaspheme who said they were Iews and were not? how much more doe they who profess the name of Christ, and are out of the vine, in a contrary nature?</p>
               <p>Wherefore all who aime to hold forth in life to his appea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance, and to attain his coming in purity and glory, must be diligent in the heavenly light, ever minding the way and mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving of the holy spirit, him that is from above, that his forme you may see, who hath the heavenly image, and the holy pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er; that so beholding him with open face as in a glass, you may be changed into the same Image, and formed thereafter, from glory to glory, by the powerfull working of the same Spirit; untill the Tabernacle be built conformable to the hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venly example, and holy pattern in body and Spirit, that as he is, so may you be in this world, that God may appear in his Temple; that as the Image of the earthly appears in the world; so the Image of the heavenly you may bear, a witnesse against them. And by drinking in the communion of that ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Spirit, and power from above, you may become as able, zealous, and willing to hold forth the heavenly in holiness, meekness, purity, patience, love, long-suffering, faith, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bedience to God, and all the fruits of the Spirit, as the Sons of the world are to hold forth the earthly, in lusts and plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sures, strife, and envy, cruelty, and oppression, and all manner the works of the flesh; that you may as truly and really, give up your bodies, minds, and strength to suffer with Christ, that he may be manifest and magnified therein, in your mortal bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies; as others who are without God in the world, doe give themselves to act according to the principles and power of the God of this world, his unrighteous wayes, worships, and fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>shions, and all his cursed courses, and the whole body of sin, and mystery of iniquity born in them.</p>
               <p>And where the Tabernacle is thus edified, and the Temple thus cleansed, there is a vessell of honour, fit for the masters
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:62426:9"/> use; that being filled with the holy Ghost, God may dwell on the earth, and take up his rest therein, his Tabernacle being with men, the appearance of the blessed day, so many souls hunger for, and <hi>Abrahams</hi> Seed longs to see, which the God of this world strongly opposes, in all whose mindes he hath blinded, and whose spirit he possesseth in disobedience to the heavenly light, for which the wrath of God remains upon that generation, till this day and for ever.</p>
               <p>Wherefore all you who wait for the Kingdome of God, and love his appearance, whose coming again is without sin, abide within, and wait in that Temple where the witness ari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>seth against the world, that in faith and patience you may be counted worthy to receive that witness, that it may arise and cover you, and that in bearing it you may come out of the world, being conformable to him, who suffered without the gates: bear his reproach, and you bear his name; touch not the unclean thing, and he will receive you for himself, in you to appear and be glorified; lifted up against the powers of darkness. You that have received the earnest of this Spirit, hath he not said, I will dwell in you, and walk in you? where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore come out from among them and be you seperate. This is the joy that is set before you, to wit, his appearance, and that glory, for the attaining whereof, we endure the present sufferings, and reproach; not to be compared therewith, for glory, immortality, eternall life.</p>
               <p>Oh friends who shall be found worthy at his coming, and in whom may he appear, and not consume them? for our God is a consuming fire; even in his holy Temple is he known, and with clean hands will he take up his rest, and in the pure heart shall he be seen; else who may dwell with everlasting burn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings? and who may abide that baptisme wherein every one shall be salted with fire at his coming.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>